<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Price Clark Personal Site</title>
    <description>This is my personal site/blog/resume.
</description>
    <link>http://gpwclark.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gpwclark.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 17:31:57 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 17:31:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 19:46:17 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gpwclark.github.io//jekyll/update/2015/05/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gpwclark.github.io//jekyll/update/2015/05/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>eCross - Psychology Paradigm for ego depletion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a javascript/html implementation of the common e-Cross paradigm used in psychological research. It is typically used by researchers to deplete participants motivation. Thank You to Steve Love for writing the bulk of the javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR BETTER VIEWING OF THE EFFECT ONLY SELECT THE OUTPUT TAB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgb(170, 170, 170); width: 100%; min-height: 300px; height: 990px;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://jsbin.com/guhas/1/embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 21:10:01 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gpwclark.github.io//2015/05/18/ecross.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gpwclark.github.io//2015/05/18/ecross.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GNU Screen</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently found myself hanging out in the terminal window a lot more. As a result, I find myself wanting to hang out in two terminal windows at the same time. Much in the same way that you may want many browser windows, each with N tabs. Screen allows you to create multiple sessions (which are ‘like’ browser windows) and populate each session with as many windows (which are ‘like’ tabs). As a bonus, screen allows you to ‘detach’ sessions (similar to minimizing a window, but more persistent) which in turn can be ‘re-attached’ later in order to resume whatever processes were running in the screen when it was detached. This is pretty supreme, especially if you’re ssh-ing all over the place, doing important scp’s, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is also here because I keep forgetting these commands and writing about them may help them stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#tips&quot;&gt;For those uninterested in the ‘walk-through’ style, click here to proceed to the condensed list of essential shortcuts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-wonderful-world-of-screen&quot;&gt;The wonderful world of Screen&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first important thing about screen is installing it. If you’re on linux, then you’ll have some easy set-up composed of something to the tune of…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install screen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but maybe you’re like me and you prefer to type the string (as a warm-up) and then sudo, followed by the same string. If you’re on a mac, screen is already there, good job apple. If you’re on a windows, well, get Cygwin… right now. You may be forced onto a windows computer for work, for economic reasons, for honor, for glory, for shizzle, but that doesn’t mean you can’t have a wonderful linux-y terminal when you want, where you want… get Cygwin and make sure to include screen during installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;opening-screen&quot;&gt;Opening Screen&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first I like to think about with screen is where I am relative to “it”. So you start out in the “display terminal”, this refers to your own terminal window, PowerShell, Git Bash, Putty, etc. Quick procedural note: if you’re on a windows and you still aren’t on Cygwin then stop reading this post and go get it, seriously. Anywho, so screen, likes to be addressed by name when you aren’t in it, but want to use it. A good place to start is with, well,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ screen -ls&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…it does exactly what you’d think, it lists the current “sessions” you have, right now, this is 0, and screen will say something like “No Sockets found in…”, what are sockets? Well, it’s a dumb word, and not really lingo the “screen” community uses. As mentioned in the beginning, screen works well with a browser metaphor. To open up a new ‘browser window’ in screen AKA a new session, you type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ screen // make sure to rename session with C-a :sessionName newSessionName&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;OR&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ screen -S myRadSession&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first option is inferior. Simply typing screen opens up a new session. The second option is better, it also opens up a new session but it has a name, forcing yourself to name a session makes you think about why you need it. If you are using your internet browser perhaps you want one browser window that has a lot of tabs related to your finances, you might name that browser window ‘money’, similarly, another browser window might have youtube, facebook, and wikipedia open, this window would be called ‘leisure’. In screen it’s the same, give your session a name so you know what sorts of windows you are going to be using in it, it is also important if you detach… but more on that later. Now, you have successfully started a session, you are in what is called a “virtual terminal”. It’s called a virtual terminal because it is a terminal emulated within a terminal, it is EXACTLY like any terminal UNLESS you hit ctrl+a. Ctrl-a is a little too obvious so in the biz we use ‘C-‘ to mean Ctrl or ‘^C’, I’m going to use ‘C-‘ because if you get up the courage to type ‘man screen’, thus revealing screen’s manual, you’ll see a lot of ‘C-‘.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;navigation&quot;&gt;Navigation&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why ‘C-a’ you ask? Well, ‘C-a’ is screen’s escape sequence. An escape sequence tells screen, ‘Hey, come out of the shadows to do something for me.’ So, in a session it might be useful to hit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a + w&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you’ll see a string appear in your window, either on the bottom or at the top that says ‘0&lt;em&gt;$ bash’, congrats, you’re in a window in a session and it’s name is 0&lt;/em&gt;$ bash. If a session is like a browser window, then a window is like browser’s tab. This means you have a session going, and it’s got one ‘tab’ called a window. Making new windows is easy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a + c&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this key combination will take you to the new window in the session, if you hit ‘C-a’ + ‘w’ again, you’ll see you now have two windows open ‘0&lt;em&gt;$ bash’ and ‘1&lt;/em&gt;$ bash’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, by hitting ‘C-a’ you tell screen listen for shortcut keys. So, ‘C-a’ is indicating you want to use a shortcut key combination and ‘c’ is one such shortcut, it creates a new window in the session. Now, you need to be able to navigate through the windows in your session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a C-space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// next window in session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a + p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// previous window in session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you have too many windows and you want to destroy one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a + k&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//hit ‘y’ to confirm the kill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you want to name each window in the session?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a + A&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// input name then hit enter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;advanced-moves&quot;&gt;Advanced Moves&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;these-are-just-from-man-screen-but-they-are-commands-i-tend-to-remember&quot;&gt;…These are just from &lt;code&gt;man screen&lt;/code&gt;, but they are commands I tend to remember.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a F //(fit)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Resize the window to the current region size.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a C-l //(redisplay)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Fully refresh the current window.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a h //(hardcopy)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Write a hardcopy of the current window to the file “hardcopy.n”..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a H //(log)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Toggle logging of the current window to the file “screenlog.n”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a [ OR C-a C-[ OR C-a &amp;lt;esc&amp;gt;//(copy)&amp;lt;/esc&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Enter copy/scrollback mode.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a ] OR C-a C-] // (paste)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 Write the contents of the paste buffer to the stdin queue of the current window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;administrative&quot;&gt;Administrative&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, there are a few things left to walk about, namely my favorite feature of screen. Screen allows you to continue a process, even if you exit out of terminal. To use this feature, you simply ‘detach’ whichever session has the window with the process you want to use. To detach you hit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-a + C-d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after this you are back to your main terminal window, from here you can create a new session, which we already want over, or you can connect to a currently running session. As mentioned before type &lt;code&gt;screen -ls&lt;/code&gt; to list all of the sessions, and from here you use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen -r baz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// to connect to detached session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen -rx baz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// to connect to attached session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you want to destroy a session, simply open it &lt;code&gt;screen -r #name#&lt;/code&gt; and use &lt;code&gt;C-a + k&lt;/code&gt; on each window in the terminal to make sure there is nothing important there. Alternatively you can just use &lt;code&gt;pkill screen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank You.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;essential-screen-shortcut-keys&quot;&gt;Essential Screen Shortcut Keys&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a great link I often refer to sometimes:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://aperiodic.net/screen/quick_reference&quot;&gt;Advanced GNU screen quick reference …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/**
*Commands to use outside of screen
*/
screen -ls          // list sessions
screen              // new session, no name
screen -S bar       // new session w/ name
screen -r baz       // connect to detached session
screen -rx baz      // connect to attached
                       session

/**
*Commands to use in screen
*/
C-a + c             // new window... within a session
C-a + space         // next window in session
C-a + p             // previous window within socket
C-a + k             // kill one window within a socket
C-a + A	            // name current window
C-a + C-d	    // detach session, keeps all windows
                       within session running
C-a + C-a           // go to previous window
C-a + C-w           // lists names of all windows in current
                       session

/**
*How do I kill this whole session thing?
*/
C-a + k             // recommended: kill all windows
                       in session &amp;amp; it closes
pkill screen        // I mean... you could do this
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 22:23:17 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gpwclark.github.io//2015/05/13/gnu_screen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gpwclark.github.io//2015/05/13/gnu_screen.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting my Linux Machine Properly Permiss-ed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am getting to the point now where I need to share my homeserver with others for development (Most notably &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.jazz.net/project/gpwclark/pettr/overview&quot;&gt;Pettr&lt;/a&gt;). So, I’m biting the bullet and mucking around with file permissions, user groups, etc… also because I’m tired of remembering to type sudo all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-undoing-a-bad-practice-of-mine&quot;&gt;First: Undoing a bad practice of mine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use services like Zend Eclipse for PHP Developers and to simplify things I just gave it my root login. No more, I am disabling root access via ssh on my computer. Doing so is simple,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /etc/ssh/sshd_config // use ctrl + W to find the line that says... 
 PermitRootLogin yes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply change the value from yes to no and then save the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;second-creating-usersgroups-and-keeping-it-consistent&quot;&gt;Second: Creating users/groups and keeping it consistent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we need a new user (with a password), and they need to belong to a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo useradd developer // new user created   
  sudo passwd developer // will prompt you to enter new UNIX password  
   sudo groupadd developers // new group created   
   sudo usermod -a -G developers developer // user is in the group&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for file permissions. I am bias given IBM was nice enough to hire me but
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/library/l-lpic1-v3-104-5/&quot;&gt;this is the most fantastic document&lt;/a&gt; 
 I’ve found to walk you through file permissions and group ownership. It’s a little verbose so below I will discuss what I’ve done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as file permissions are concerned, make sure you understand what all 10 (or 11 now?) bits mean when you see a listing like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-rw-rw-r-- 1 remote remote 10025 Mar 31 21:35 built-editor.css  
   -rw-rw-r-- 1 remote remote 8188 Mar 31 21:35 built-editor.js  
   drwxr-xr-x 6 root root 4096 Feb 26 23:48 eclipse  
   -rw-rw-r-- 1 remote remote 59012644 Mar 27 22:26 eclipse-orion.gtk.x86_64.zip  
   drwxr-xr-x 8 root root 4096 May 22 02:39 org.eclipse.orion.client&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest though, you may end up memorizing a few of the octal commands for chmod but I think the most intuitive way of going about it is detailed in the IBM developerworks article. If you want to change the permissions for the user, or group, or other, simply use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chmod [u|g|o]+[r|w|x] filename&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i.e.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chmod ugo+rwx filename // gives all access to everyone  
   sudo chmod ug+rw filename // gives user and group read/write access  
   sudo chmod o+rx filename // gives others read and execute privileges.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it is a little easier to think about setting file permissions that explicitly, especially when starting out. Now, to put them to use. In my scenario, I want to place a folder, which I’ll call developers, at the root of my website so users have access to a testing environment immediately viewable on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir /var/www/development // folder created  
   sudo chgrp developers /var/www/development // group ownership changed&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-ensuring-groups-have-proper-permissions-for-all-children-filesfolders&quot;&gt;Third: Ensuring groups have proper permissions for all children files/folders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have done some light mucking around with file permissions in the past chances are you’ve gotten annoyed that a file/folder you created doesn’t necessarily enforce the permission/ownership rights of it’s parents. This is important, the administrator may want to add files to a folder that someone else created without necessarily giving them access. However, if you create a folder for a development group, you want every folder/file that is a child of that new development folder to be readable, writable, and executable by your group. Furthermore, you want this to be automatic, i.e. after each ‘mkdir’ and ‘touch’. Enter the setuid and setgid bits for file permissions. By setting these, you can allow a user or a group to run executables as if they were the root user. On the other end, setting these bits on folders allow any child of the folder to &lt;strong&gt;inherit that folder’s group ID&lt;/strong&gt; The IBM developerworks article I added has all the necessary background, so I’ll skip ahead to the code part:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/*  
    * group write access and assurance that all children   
    * in development folder will be owned by group  
    */  
   sudo chmod g+ws development&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Note: any files already in the folder will not be affected by this command. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Setuid#setgid_on_directories&quot;&gt;This wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; has the line of code you would want to use to set the extant children’s folders with the permissions you intend with chmod g+s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fourth-what-else-will-a-user-need----the-ability-to-run-programs&quot;&gt;Fourth: What else will a user need? – The ability to run… programs&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 22:19:53 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gpwclark.github.io//2015/05/13/multi_user.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gpwclark.github.io//2015/05/13/multi_user.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
